在上一集中
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
有一套啊 你这小滑头！
Well, aren't you the clever one?
你正好给那些胆敢让我失望之人
You shall serve as a constant reminder to those who dare
做个警示！
fail me.
什么？！
What?!
现在有三枚钥匙了
Three keys are accounted for.
看来这地儿现在由我做主
It would seem I have the run of the place.
啊 在这儿呐！
Ah, there you are.
无论红蜘蛛有何企图
The fate of Cybertron now rests in Starscream's hands...
塞博特恩的命运都掌握在他手中了…
whatever his intention.
请原谅我的不请自来 威震天陛下
Please pardon my unannounced visit, Lord Megatron.
小人有礼物敬呈于您…
But I have come bearing a peace offering.
天下没有白吃的午餐 说吧 红蜘蛛
Few things of value come without a price. So, tell me, Starscream.
你想要什么回报？
What is it that you wish in return?
小人只愿重回霸天虎之列
Only to be a Decepticon once again.
我现在的副官是骇翼
Dreadwing is my first lieutenant now.
在我缺席期间发生的变故 我已坦然接受
And I accept that much has changed during my absence.
我只想为您效力
I only wish to serve you
我唯一真正的主人
my one true master
任您差遣 绝无怨言
in any way that you deem fit.
你此次立下大功 我深感欣慰 红蜘蛛
I am deeply impressed by your accomplishment, Starscream.
你的贡献 我必将善加用之
And know that I will put your offerings to good use
无论结果如何…
whatever the outcome.
啊 结果？什么结果？！
Uh, outcome? Of what?
赶快把击倒从墙中挖出来！
See to it that Knockout is extracted from the wall.
啊…
Ah.
人家自由了！
It's good to be back.
这次您想知道什么呢 我的君王？
Now, what will we be fishing for today, my liege?
红蜘蛛的真实意图！
Starscream's true motives.
霸天虎们 我怀着沉痛的心情
Decepticons, it is with deep sorrow
向大家宣告…
that I note for the log
威震天的火种已经熄灭了
Megatron's spark has been extinguished.
红蜘蛛…万…岁！
All hail Starscream.
红蜘蛛万岁！
All hail Starscream!
哎呀呀 你可真是惜时如金呐
Well, well. You certainly didn't waste any time.
什么？！
What?!
我刚才看见你已经死了！
I just watched you perish!
昔日的我未曾覆灭
I did not perish then
而今的我与你相随！
and I'm very much with you now...
此时此刻你我同在…
the present you
恰如彼时彼刻！
as well as the past.
红蜘蛛万岁！
All hail Starscream!
本座听不见…
I can't hear you!
红蜘蛛万岁！
All hail Starscream!
再来一次！
One more time!
红蜘蛛万岁！
All hail Starscream!
沙发看戏…
This is going to be juicy.
呃…您正在小人脑中 是么？
Ah! You're inside my head, aren't you?
这是大脑神经接入器
The cortical psychic patch.
如你所见 此地只有记忆 没有秘密
You see, there are no secrets in here... only your memories.
你既无法操纵其内容
You cannot manipulate their content
也无法修饰其结果
or modify their outcome.
你我所见的是曾经发生的事实！
What we see is how it happened.
如果你想成为一个真正的首领 红蜘蛛
If you want to be a true leader, Starscream
那就不要走威震天的老路
then stray from Megatron's path
你要带领霸天虎走向和平
and lead the Decepticons toward peace.
我会真心考虑停战的
I would be willing to consider a truce...
只要你真心向我称臣 擎天柱
if you would be willing to bow before me, Optimus Prime.
你又违背本座的命令了！
You have defied my orders yet again!
这是我的失误 长官
My mistake, Commander Starscream.
叫我陛下！
It is Lord!
你没听说吗？
Haven't you heard?
本座如今贵为霸天虎统领！
I lead the Decepticons now.
我们看到哪儿了？
Now, where did we leave off?
喔对
Oh, yes.
红蜘蛛万岁？
"All hail Starscream"?
提一个明显的小小争议：
A rather obvious motif, Starscream.
你竟自视比我更有资格领导霸天虎？
You deem yourself more able to lead the Decepticons than myself?!
不！不再是了！
No, not anymore.
在经历如此之多的失败以后 主人
I have learned from my many failures, master.
我亲爱的成员们
Esteemed members of my armada...
你们即将见证 本座长久以来不懈追求的光荣时刻
you now stand upon the very precipice of glory... to meet the destiny which I have so tenaciously worked toward.
霸天虎的领导权应该轮流坐庄！
Dynamic leadership of the Decepticons.
那是克隆体说的 不是我！
That clone said it, not me!
看来 你并未阻止任何颠覆我政权的言行
It seems you would stop at nothing to disrupt my rule
包括那场行刺！
including assassination.
那是他们的主意 不是我的！
It was their idea, not mine!
我们有了这种听从你指挥的生物
With this creature under your control and at our disposal
我们可以用他去了结威震天
we might employ it to terminate Megatron
夺取霸天虎的控制权
allowing us to rule the Decepticons.
这里没有什么克隆体 这也是他们的主意？
I see no clones here. Was this their idea, too?
小人对此毫无印象…
I don't remember any of this.
我那时一定是在抽风呢
I must have been half-crazed at the time
肯定是没能量吃 饿昏了头！
a victim of Energon deficiency.
告诉我为什么要欢迎你？
Tell me why I should welcome back someone
你生命中的每一次脉冲 都用来刺伤我
whose every waking impulse has been to thwart me
暗算我
undercut me
推翻我！
overthrow me?!
绝非如此！
Not true.
小人一直视陛下之命重于泰山！
I have always put your well-being before my own.
这就是所谓的“重于泰山”？
How does this revolting chapter constitute attending to my well-being?
我只是想帮您
I was simply trying to help
以免黑暗能量污染您的圣体！
by ridding you of the dark matter polluting your body.
看来我拥有唯一一个
Seems I possess the only thing that
能让你从病榻上重新站起来的东西！
would allow you to rise off that slab and walk again
最最亲爱的威震天…
my dearest Megatron.
我甚至为您险些被活埋！
I even risked being buried alive for you.
我…我没有抛下您 主人
I did not abandon you, master.
我回来…是要救您！
I returned to save you!
火种可鉴 威震天陛下
Look into my spark, Lord Megatron.
我是真心的！
My intentions were true.
真是如此吗 红蜘蛛？
Were they, Starscream?
你这辈子真心过吗？
Were they ever?!
现在轮到谁翻不了身啦？
Well, now who has hit rock bottom?
说什么？对不起
What's that? I'm sorry.
隔着一座五行山 我什么都听不清
I can't hear you beneath all that rubble.
哈哈…告辞了 威震天陛下！
Ha ha... Farewell, Lord Megatron.
愿你一锈到底！
May you rust in peace!
不过 这种遭遇对你来说是小儿科
But you have survived far worse.
如果你自己逃了出来
If you managed to free yourself
就会怪罪我见死不救
you would blame me for your setback.
你发火的时候 我肯定会理亏
And there is nowhere that I could possible escape from your wrath.
更不用说
Or, worse yet
那些傻瓜随从肯定会来找你
your mindless followers will come looking for you
并因为营救你而立功
and take credit for your rescue...
这个功劳 应该属于我！
credit that could rightfully be mine!
啊啊！威震天！
Ah! Megatron!
听我一句忠告…
A word of advice?
…别再把心里话大声喊出来了！
Stop thinking aloud.
我已经不想再玩这个游戏了！
I don't want to play this game anymore.
拿走钥匙吧！
Take the keys.
就当这事儿没发生过！
We'll pretend I was never here.
没门儿 红蜘蛛！
No, Starscream.
此事只能有两种结果
There are only two possible outcomes
待我彻底看透你这颗扭曲的心灵之后
based upon what I find here in your twisted, little mind.
若是我发现你没有资格重回霸天虎之列
If I do not deem that you are worthy of rejoining the Decepticons
那今天就是你的末日！
you will perish on this very day.
啊 杀死我是不是过于极端了？
Ah. Isn't termination rather extreme?
我是指…您平日的教训就很有效了…不是么？
I mean, a really good trouncing usually straightens me out, doesn't it?
不 主人 不要！
No, master. Nooo!
您何不对我作为霸天虎的天赋善加利用呢？
Why wouldn't you wish to harness my talents for the Decepticon cause?
您知道我的狡猾也能派上用场！
You and I have so much deviousness to offer.
就当是为您的回归献上的贺礼！
Consider it a "welcome home" present.
您瞧 我也可以变得慷慨 陛下！
See how generous I can be, my liege?
你只在必要的时候
When it suits you...
主人 那就是你的计划？
Master, that's your plan?!
复活死掉的汽车人 让我们挨揍？
Bring Autobots back from the dead to attack us?!
随后 你立即就变得傲慢无礼！
At other times, you could be quite insulant.
我很抱歉
Apologies.
我只是…初次杀死那个汽车人时 费了不少周折！
It's just that I'd gone to so much trouble to terminate the Autobot in the first place.
只有像战士一样杀死他才会如此！
Trouble would have been facing him as a gladiator.
小人一向认为智慧才是最犀利的武器
I've always considered my wits to be my sharpest weapon.
慢着
Wait.
你们想算计我！
You two are up to something.
你从不吸取教训 红蜘蛛
You never learn, Starscream.
你的傲慢凌驾于智慧之上！
Your arrogance will trump your wits every time.
你伤不了我
You cannot harm me
黑暗能量已经流遍了我的经脉 我已不可战胜！
while Dark Energon flows through my veins! I am invincible!
你个头很大
You're a big one.
吸收时间要长一点了
This could take a while.
什么？她把杀掉他的功劳安在自己头上？！
What? She's taking credit for scraping him now, too?
那是我干的！
That was my doing!
噢不！不要！呃…别开枪！
Oh, no! No! Eh... No!
有什么遗言吗 烟幕？
Any last words, Smokescreen?
我的变形齿轮
My T-Cog.
嗯 只是一个暂时的小插曲
A, uh... a temporary setback.
还有其他汽车人 其他的变形齿轮
Other Autobots, other T-Cogs.
我们很快就能找到另一个
We shall find a replacement soon enough.
那不够快 现在就要！
Not "soon enough". Now.
呃…啊！怎么？！
Huh? Ah! What?
汽车人！
Autobots!
我的变形齿轮！
My T-Cog!
你已经不能再飞了？
You no longer possess the ability to take flight?!
是的…我刚想说这件事…
Uh, yes, I-I was going to bring that up.
您可以想象 我目前的窘境令我无比痛苦！
And, as you might imagine, my predicament pains me to no end.
很幸运 先驱号的追踪系统\N还能追踪到威震天的战舰
Fortunately, the Harbingers' tracking systems have remained synched with Megatron's warship.
当然我们要先想个办法登上去
Of course, we shall require a means of reaching the...
啊？你们能变形？
Huh? You can transform?!
啊对 你们当然能变形！
Uh, of course you can.
否则怎么飞到飞船上去？
How else would you fly to the ship?
我只是想考验一下 你们都通过了
That was a test in which you all... passed.
我希望您考虑下帮我重拾飞机形态
I hope that you might see fit to express your gratitude for the Omega keys
当做我送来“终极之钥”的回报
by restoring my jet mode.
毕竟
After all
能飞的我 对您的用处更大
would I not be more valuable to you with wings?
喔 我每次变形都帅得掉渣！
Ooh, I do transform with an exceptional sense of style.
呃…我把这句话说出口了 是吗？
I said that aloud, didn't I?
威震天不念旧情 想把我干掉
Megatron tried to extinguish my spark in cold blood
还有那个一心想取代我的混蛋毒蜘蛛
then all but replaced me with that traitorous wretch, Airachnid.
她竟然丢下我不管！
She abandoned me
让我自生自灭！
left me for scrap!
所以 干嘛不过河拆桥呢？
So why not rat them out?
没人想把你赶出霸天虎阵营
No one asked you to leave the Decepticon fold.
可我当时并不招人待见！
But I wasn't exactly made to feel welcome at the time.
主人 求您了！
Master, please
再给我一次机会吧 我给您磕头了！
give me one more chance! I beg of you!
对于我痛悔往昔并愿意为您\N奉献一切的心情 您无动于衷
Despite the fact that I had seen the error of my ways and dedicated my spark to you.
我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe...
认清了自我 那个自始至终的我
of who I am... of who I was always meant to be.
红蜘蛛 副指挥官
Starscream, second in command
威震天陛下的心腹侍从
humble servant to Lord Megatron.
直到你又有机会推翻我！
Until the next opportunity arises to subvert me.
病人今天状况如何？
And how is the patient doing today?
老样子
Same old.
保持这种植物人状态 真是让他无地自容
An inglorious fate that he should remain in this vegetative state.
正相反 威震天的身体也许成了废铁
On the contrary. Megatron's body may be scrap metal
但他的思维还是很活跃的
but his mind is still percolating.
你自己知道就行了！
Keep that to yourself.
那该死的声波好像有千里眼和顺风耳！
That blasted Soundwave sees and hears everything.
他是霸天虎的耳目嘛
The eyes and ears of the Decepticons.
只要他们的主子一天不醒 他们就是群无头苍蝇
Well, as long as their master remains in limbo, so does their cause.
霸天虎急需一位强悍的 警醒的领袖
The Decepticons deserve a strong, alert leader.
这位领袖也需要一个忠诚的副官
One who would require a loyal second in command.
要想坐上副官的位置 必须干得漂亮点 才能让那个“耳目”闭嘴
A candidate would need to earn that post by making a strong case to said eyes and ears.
需要发发慈悲吗 红蜘蛛陛下？
A case for showing mercy, Lord Starscream?
啊哦
Uh-oh.
这机器有快进快退按钮吗？
Does this thing have a fast-forward button
或是删除也行啊！
or better yet, erase?
击倒 麻烦你向声波讲一下 专家的治疗意见
Knockout, if you would be so kind as to provide your expert medical opinion to Soundwave
以便记录在案
for the historical record.
简单来说 如果没有外力协助 威震天会永远保持这种假死状态
Simply put, unaid, Megatron could remain in this deathless slumber forever.
我们的主人不会希望自己成为这个样子
Our master would not have wanted to be seen this way
眼看着他的灵魂被禁锢 我们却无所事事 这不公平
to stand idly by while he remains captive in his own body... is not just.
脑电波的活动不能证明他拥有意识
Brain-Wave activity... not evidence of consciousness
只是陷入了无穷的梦境 威震天或许永远都无法醒过来
but merely of an endless dream from which Megatron may never wake.
声波 我们必须面对现实
Soundwave, we must face reality.
我们已经痛失威震天
Megatron is lost to us.
唯一体面的选择 就是让他解脱
The only honorable option would be to show him mercy.
只是拨动一个开关而已
A simple throw of the switch.
等威震天醒来以后
When Megatron comes out of it
就不是把我塞回墙壁里那么简单了！
he'll do more than just stick me back in that wall.
他会把红蜘蛛的脑袋砍下来 还有我的！
He'll have Starscream's head and mine!
不过…如果我在机器关闭之前 就强行拔出接头的话
But... if I disconnect before a proper power-down
连接就会中断
the link is severed and...
老大将永远无法从红蜘蛛的脑中逃脱
the big guy will never emerge from Starscream's head.
这儿…没问题吧？
Everything okay here?
就是看看接头插好没！
Just checking cable integrity.
还有别的事情能拿来评估你的忠诚度吗？
Is it any wonder that I've come to value loyalty above all else?
这个…您知道
Well, you know
咱们可是霸天虎…
we are Decepticons.
我相信即便是您亲爱的骇翼也并非完美
I'm sure that even your beloved Dreadwing isn't perfect.
人无完人 红蜘蛛
No one is perfect, Starscream
但如同其分离的孪生兄长一般
but like his departed twin
骇翼他懂得荣耀！
Dreadwing understands honor.
苏醒吧 战士
Awaken, warrior.
醒过来 侍奉你的新主人！
Rise and serve your new master!
天震只侍奉一个主人
Skyquake serves only one master.
很好
Excellent.
你的忠诚和奉献精神将成为军队的好榜样
Your loyalty and devotion will set a fine example for the troops.
不必拘谨 天震
No need to be timid, Skyquake.
俯首称臣吧
You may bow.
你没听懂我的话
You fail to grasp my meaning.
派我来这里执行任务的
I am here on a mission
是我唯一的主人 威震天
assigned to me by my one master... Megatron.
对 他嘛…
Yes... him.
很不幸 威震天已经离我们而去了
Sadly, Megatron is... no longer with us.
不可能！
Impossible.
为什么所有人都难以接受事实？
Why is this so difficult for everyone to accept?
啊 强大的天震葬身于此
Ah, the grave site of the mighty Skyquake.
生前你不假思索地拒绝我的领导
So quick to reject my authority while you lived.
但作为被我复活的第一名战士
But, as the first of my reanimated warriors
你应该听我号令！
you shall bow to my command.
是的…黑暗能量之力…是我的了！
Ah! Yes! Power of Dark Energon, be mine!
融为一体 哈哈哈…我感觉到了！
Symbiosis. Hahaha... I can feel it!
他先前不是死去了么？
I understand he perished that day.
嗯…他既非生者亦非亡者
Well, Skyquake is neither living nor dead
现在一定仍在另一重维度空间中游荡着
and no doubt continues to wander through some dimensional neverealm
寻找他的断肢
in search of his missing limb.
你够聪明的话 就别将此事告诉船上的任何人
It would be wise to keep that to yourself around the warship.
完了…
Awkward.
但…您的意思是…？
B-But, does this mean...
是的 我允许你重回我们的队伍
Yes. I will allow you to return to our ranks
只因这样比与你为敌更为有利！
if only because you are more valuable beside me than against me.
我的个娘啊…感谢火种源！
Oh! Thank the Allspark!
在你缺席期间霸天虎已经因为内讧而四分五裂了
Infighting has nearly destroyed the Decepticons during your absence.
如果我们还想征服塞博特恩就必须团结一致
We must operate as a united front if we are to revive and conquer Cybertron.
所以谁都不可有二心 击倒！
That means each and every one of us, Knockout.
威震天可真是会笼络人心啊…
Megatron sure knows how to patch things up.
对吧…骇…
Eh, Dreadwing?
骇翼？
Dreadwing?